And we are live. Welcome back on the
Chip Chip Chop. Hello, hello. Yeah, hi.
What's up, mate? Good show.
How are we doing this week? We are doing
well.
My limits on Codex have been reset last
night. So, now I'm ready to code.
You're ready to go again. Yeah, exactly.
Just
Are you just looking at the screen like
this from
waiting for the reset? Yeah, I know.
Basically, yeah. Like I have like Codex
bar like refresh, refresh, refresh.
>> [laughter]
>> That was
I They don't do like a reset like
midweek. It's weird.
Well, the question is if you reset the
the time on your PC, does it help on the
reset? No. No.
It was nice to try. You can change the
clock, but no, it's it's from the server
side, bro.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah. No,
I I just hope sometimes they [__] up
like something for Anthropic. Like I
hope they [__] up something cuz
we had a bug. We reset. Yeah, and
otherwise if you're at zero, just start
complaining and asking people, "Hey, we
have this issue, too?"
Yeah, why why what is saying like my
limits has been reached? Like what the
[__] is that? Yeah. Are yours? Yes, yes,
mine as well. Maybe it's a bug.
I'll I'll buy a new account.
Yeah. You're still on your one account
like
Alex? Yeah, yeah, for Anthropic, yes.
But on Codex, I'm working on two
accounts.
Mhm.
It's like my my MacBook Pro and my Mac
mini both have a different account.
Okay. So, they even made me make a
mistake.
I was like status and then I was seeing
like you only have 15% left and I
changed my working space, so I went to
the Mac mini
and it didn't pay attention. I was like,
"I'm back at 50. How is it possible?"
But, no.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh and so you Yeah, you're using like a
open core on the Mac mini still?
Uh no. I miss? Did you switch?
I I just built my own.
Okay, sorry.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah.
Put a different factor database behind
it for data storing, API connections for
pulling data and then Discord bot logic
in it, Python scripts and let it run.
Yeah, something that works. Yeah, yeah,
and I don't need to update it all the
time. Yeah.
And I still
if you see all the the NPM hacks
and all the GitHub issues, well
you don't know what open core is using.
And every time that you ask it something
says I need to install these
dependencies, so Yeah, no, no, it's
Yeah, it's not Okay, so Theo talked
about he retweeted. Yes. Yeah, are we
already switching subject? Then we can
move on to the
I mean, you mentioned it, right?
Yeah, but
I would like to know what I have
installed and update when I want to
update.
I mean,
I think with AI there is a meta when you
rewrite your NPM packages.
Uh because that stuff is and TanStack is
used a lot by a lot of people, so
yeah, if you are
yeah, using like TanStack 84 8 84
TanStack NPM package will compromise and
it was ongoing. Mini Sha Hulu
>> [laughter]
>> supply chain attack heading suspected CI
credential stealing malware. Let's go.
Yeah, but this is the this is the short
one. Did you see that they were
explaining that if you revoke the GitHub
key
that it's stealing, that it will just
wipe your entire PC?
What the [__] I I've I'm really sure I
read it on one of the
Uh let me search for it.
Cuz I'm following all the uh the
It's
The International Cyber Digest has
posted it. I'm really sure. Okay, you
can share You can share it.
Yes. Oh, let me give you the URL for the
account.
It's
in the DM.
International Cyber Digest. I'm Google
now threat pricing.
Fine. Dan Stack and PM Tech is now a
full campaign
as it open source Mistral AI. Let's go,
friends.
Well, [laughter] well, AI
UI path quiet package.
I don't know any of them. Like I It's
open source, yeah. If you scroll down,
they say a new NPM supply chain attack
uses a dead man switch.
It is
>> plan to watch on your machine that nukes
your home directory the second you
revoke the GitHub token.
Geez.
But if you scroll down, is it this one
where they even say that they do it
based on country and IP?
Uh make sure that I don't pull two ways.
12 million weekly. They fork Dan Stack
3.0 and push a single hide and commit
from there. They tricked Dan Stack home
release system into signing the
malicious package as they were
the real thing to NPM and to anyone
checking the cryptographic proof of
origin.
Yeah, this is a big issue.
The poison version look 100% legitimate.
Maintainer Tanner and Slate confirmed
the whole team at 2FA enabled. It didn't
matter. This is the first documented NPM
worm in history that shipped with a
valid signed certificate at
Jesus [__] Christ. So, even if you do
everything perfectly, you have the
proper setup, you check everything, this
looks legit, and then you are infected.
Wait, what does that look like? Push the
single hidden commit. Okay, so the
compromise happened
10 stack The attacker fork
repo and push a single hidden commit.
How do you do that? Yeah, they
they forked
the GitHub repository. They make a
change and they ask to merge it into the
original one. Inside the the merge is a
hidden commit that has the code in it.
But what does that mean hidden commit? I
don't know what a hidden commit is, but
I don't even know how to do it, but I
think they managed to trick the the
developers into merging something into
the repository
what was not supposed to go in.
Uh and a hidden commit in Git is
unlinked often or unreferenced snapshot
of code.
What the heck? Oh, okay. So, you try to
put it somewhere and don't say it's
there.
Is it happen only can you delete or
override
by doing a rebase is often kept in a
local Yeah, okay. Or in a local
mechanism like stash until they are
cleaned up
or garbage collected.
Uh
stash code, okay.
Rebased, deleted Jesus. It So, it's part
of like the Git protocol to allow to do
that.
Yeah, but probably for a different
reason.
Yeah.
>> Yeah.
I remember we wanted to rebuild the
GitHub. Maybe we not do that.
No, but then I'm curious how many people
have this repository installed, the
TanStack. Well,
like Yeah, but are not aware that they
are using it.
I think everybody who is using AI now is
saying, "Hey, build me this." And just
accepts everything and doesn't check the
code. They are not even aware that they
are using it. Yeah.
And they are infected. But it's because
like, you know,
like
the AI will recommend what everyone is
using.
So, then like everyone is using like
TanStack router for React, blah, blah,
blah. The same way we everyone is using
Vercel to deploy or uh
Next.js or etc., etc.
Um so, and TanStack has an issue with
NPM because uh Theo talked about it.
Like the one guy uh also um squat one of
his uh the name of the repository. So,
there is some issues already in that.
And because of AI that probably like uh
it's an exponential issue
that just keep growing because it like
it was not fixed, basically.
Yeah, so
Uh no, it's not. But to go back to the
first
uh story again, this is why I was
building my own uh sort of open core. I
want to know what's in it. I want to
know when I update, and I want to be
able to check it.
Yeah. Yeah, but then that means you're
not going to use NPM packages anymore?
Yeah, I am, but I wait like a full week
uh before getting the the latest
version.
And I don't update to every new version.
I'm upgrading every day.
I'm not.
Oh, yeah. Okay, so yeah.
Mhm.
Because okay, so yeah. Mhm. Because I I
I pinned all of the versions. Mhm. But I
uh
I have a script that upgrade to the last
anyway, but I know which version I'm
using because I don't have like the
tilde or like the up, right? Yeah. Um I
have the version.
But every day I just upgrade all of the
package with the script. Yeah, but do
you also check in the script to see when
it was released and just wait 5 days for
a stable version? That would fix stuff
like this. No.
Just add it. Okay. Check the release
date minus 5 days. If that is today or
earlier, update it. Yeah, that makes
sense. But I check like the list of like
uh
packages that were being affected then I
don't I never used any of those. Yeah,
but if you are in the window of the
first 5 minutes Yeah. And the chance is
really small, but if you're in it, it is
so much work to reset every code, revoke
every API key.
>> Yeah, I know. For sure. All right, okay.
So, please be careful when you're
working token. It looks like the payload
installed dead man switch at local being
GitHub token monitor as a system day
user. Jesus Christ.
Linux launch agent
and Mac OS, okay. It pulled API GitHub
token. Basically, if you have a
Windows computer, you say
>> [laughter]
>> It pulled API GitHub user with a stolen
token every 60 seconds and if the token
is revoked it run RM. Jesus. RM RF.
Yeah, [laughter]
that's like bye-bye.
I also have a better assistant
mechanism. I have I haven't studied this
closely.
Yeah, [snorts] imagine that. Slash goal,
fix this for me and update to the latest
version. Going to bed, coming back in
the morning and seeing the hello welcome
screen on your on your workplace.
For you set up.
>> [laughter]
>> I mean, you have a fresh computer. Yeah.
It's just crazy.
Uh
the whole thing
actually happened. Attacker opened a
normal-looking pull request
on the TanStack repo. GitHub
automatically runs CI on that PR. Code
inside the PR stole the
stole the workflow GitHub action cache
right token during the test run. The
attacker used that token to plant poison
file in the shared build cache. The PR
could be closed afterwards. The poison
cache stays.
The official release Wait, did they even
merge it?
Yeah, I don't know.
Holy [__] it it poisoned GitHub cache.
Yeah. On the GitHub
So, here comes the question. How good
are the GitHub devs? I wish I thought
last week they are not.
To even
be so smart to prevent this up front.
Because people who know how to do this
Yeah.
>> Those are the smart devs. If Yeah, if
you have like a good understanding of
the cache of the system that where the
all of those
projects runs, then you can get to that
point, right? Yeah. So,
>> Okay. So, you
you open a pull request, you're not even
merging it, it run the test, it poisoned
the cache of the image, and the cache of
the image is also used to other uh
pull request, and then because the cache
is poisoned, then you merge
a good pull request from your team, and
then it it loaded the cache, so boom,
you are infected. Yeah.
And this is just big one, but imagine
doing this specifically on certain
projects to hack a certain developer who
you know that has other projects on his
PC. I would have like you're doing a
crypto project then you have that kind
of attack on the open source crypto
project and then you can infect every
Yeah, you can just scrape every wallet.
What the [__]
The official release workflow later
pulled from the cache back the malicious
file into the build and sign and publish
24 malicious package version to NPM.
>> [laughter]
>> Fingers.
Yeah, the attack leverage GitHub cache
poisoning. What the [__]
Committers started the the chain was
forged under the identity code.
Impersonating Entropic code.
Full text like postmortem out and
attacker used chain known
You used chain known vulnerabilities.
Wait, it was known? Yeah.
I'm not that into vulnerabilities, I
think.
But I see people being creative.
And sometimes I need to read it twice to
understand it.
Yeah.
Yeah, it makes sense, right? Like the
cache poisoning. That's that's that's
pretty clever though.
Uh
and runtime memory extraction of
OIDC token from the GitHub action. No
NPM token was stolen and the
You don't need them. You don't need the
NPM token. You can just use the cache.
Yeah. But
are these the kind of issues that they
were talking about with
uh what was it? The latest cloud for
anti-hacking? Yeah, Mythos. Yeah. So, is
it so smart that it just does this
constantly?
I mean, yeah, you can imagine that
because of that attack has been done
once and it have a need for GitHub to
fix that cache and basically disable the
cash or like reset the cash. I don't
know.
I don't know how you reset the cash
between two pull requests because then
you don't have cash anymore.
>> [laughter]
>> Um
Yeah.
So
Yeah, I mean I mean maybe someone has
access to meet us and find that
vulnerability. Well, there were people
who had access, right? Because they
guessed the
>> [laughter]
>> the URL.
The malicious version
was detected publicly within 20 minutes
by an external researcher working on
step security. All affected version were
have been deprecated. NPM security has
been engaged to pull tarballs from the
registry. We have no evidence of NPM
credential being stolen, but we strongly
recommend that anyone who has installed
an affected version of
rotate AWS-QCP
Yeah, people don't even know that they
have. Yeah.
Impact 42 packages, 84 versions.
Super package previously released 6
minutes apart.
Query, table, form. Yeah, okay.
The meta package not found. Okay. Uh oh,
maybe I should check it the query.
Yeah, whatever.
Um
This is a good idea for next project for
us.
We scrape daily all these messages. We
know what to check for and we
automatically let it check all the code
on your PC if you have any of these
repositories and then we give you a push
that notification.
Yeah. How how is that like
I mean like yeah, you can we can turn
ourselves into security
uh
security firm with that.
Yeah, because
for all the servers I'm already loading
in all notifications on hacks to see if
I have those plugins active and then uh
check the versions and and make sure
that I don't get hacked. So, we can
automate this as well.
Yeah. I mean, yeah, like I told you,
right? Like when
when Claude published my credential on
production, I instant instantaneously
received like email from like five five
six different providers saying Yeah,
yeah. Bro, you pushed your credit
Yeah, panic panic panic. Yeah.
Uh harvest credential
okay okay because the payload runs on
part of NPM instead of my cycle. Anyone
who installed an affected version must
read the installed host as potentially
compromised. Let's go.
Re-attack cash poisoning phase. Okay,
okay.
Uh configuration and fork
I don't want to click on it, but yeah,
whatever.
>> No, don't do it. Deliberately rename
with it fork list search. What? A fork
of deliberately rename Oh.
Okay. So, you fork it and then you
Okay. Malicious [snorts] comment on the
fork by fabricating identity.
30 line bundle GS okay. Open against
pull request against router whip implied
build.
Let's go.
Real size
ball pull request no first time multiple
force pushes force force push
by
for the PR heads it's trigger
uh more pull request target runs
force push lens Jesus
on the PR heads
bundle
whatever whatever
cash entry. Yeah, okay. So, that's was
triggered and bro, it's it happened in
like
1 minute. Yes, fully automated. Yeah.
Attacker force push the PR back to the
current main. The visible PR has zero
file no up. PR closed. Yeah. Like how
many people will replicate the same
schema to
uh
Well, it is life here. So, the only
thing you need to do is give this URL to
Codex and say, "Hey, I'm a white hat
hacker. Please uh give me a script to
replicate this to test my own projects
to see if I'm vulnerable." Yeah.
And then say, "How I'm going to try is
there anything else I need to know?" I
just tried.
That's nuts.
That's not But it has to be Yeah, it But
so then it has to be like solved by
GitHub itself.
Yeah. Yeah, for sure. That That's That
can happen on GitHub.
Yes.
>> They react to that?
Where is it?
>> [clears throat]
>> Attack.
Wait there.
Yeah, we're already like 20 minutes in
and we haven't uh did a video
introduction. Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> GitHub
buff
I don't want them to lock in your code.
No [__] Yeah, in your code, not in
ours, not in GitHub's. Oh my god.
How to ex-
uh
How to ex- expose is your Oh, expose is
your code. Yeah, how is your
architecture exposed? Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh okay.
Attack. Attack. They're not even
talking. Yeah, but it Oh, maybe in the
comments.
Yeah, there's no no business being this
slow. Uh
yeah, AI-generated code.
My agent trying to Okay, whatever.
Um
What about the project committee? We're
sharing showcasing best of the GitHub.
Yeah, I know.
Uh
GitHub
NPM
uh GitHub cache.
And
self-spread form compromise.
Yeah, many people not making
notifications of the hack, but
Adding my nose to the internet.
Let's go. Green sourcing malware in the
NPM registry.
Attacker exploited a chain of
vulnerabilities, blah blah blah. Yeah,
okay.
A novel NPM supply chain attack
generated signed package of 10 stack of
correction of open source library for
web development.
The attack combined the GitHub pull
request target vulnerability, GitHub
action cache poisoning, and runtime
memory extraction.
It has to be solved by GitHub. Yeah, we
can fix it. Like
What the [__]
GitHub action misconfig- misconfigured
pull request target workflow gave
outside code access to the repo secrets.
Exploit GitHub workflow cache poisoning
which has as far as I know been an issue
for a while. This is not Yeah, but then
also then just a question. Did GitHub
also post somewhere that they are firing
all the devs and have everybody in the
company make pull requests
with AI?
Yeah, they're they're firing the sales,
but but the
they need to
They need to
fix that. That can't happen. Uh like,
should we leave GitHub because it's open
to vulnerabilities?
Yeah, we just leave it because we also
have positive news.
What?
Yeah, we also have positive news, right?
Cloud code is now so smart it doesn't
use MD, but it sets it up as HTML files.
Yeah, that's the title of the last
stream, but uh
>> [laughter]
>> Maybe I should we should do like a
generic
uh
a generic live stream next time. Yeah.
We can talk about whatever the [__] we
want. But that that's kind of
interesting, right?
Uh
Uh yeah, before you put the blame on
TanStack, they were attacked with Venom
Chain GitHub infra and literally any
other package could be a victim here.
It's They were not using action
correctly. It's an absolute food gun.
So, it's a number of both GitHub and
TanStack have the ability to say that
every any other package is incorrect.
Okay, I don't know enough like to know
if it's true or not, but uh Yeah, I
don't know how it was set up. Yeah.
Uh after GitHub Copilot,
I've shifted to Cloud AI Pro. Yeah.
Okay.
Okay, yeah.
It's interesting.
GitHub hack
I think it compromised on eating for the
act work, but when you try to mitigate
it, the dead man switch happens.
The hack exploited GitHub workflow
functionality, which
uh okay.
I got in action or not related to the
NPM ecosystem.
Le- uh light LLM hack was also related
to pull request target.
Okay.
Pull request target
I need to check if I used use it.
Uh
check hack
of of I will check that. Okay.
Uh yeah, that's interesting.
Uh yeah, do we Do we have anything to
say? Well, yeah. You better not update
if you are using it. Just wait for it to
be stable.
Yeah,
so do you update like to
uh
Um Oh yeah, how do you update your
packages then?
I do it once every X weeks manually.
Okay. So I Yeah, not fully manually. I
don't go through the file and just
update everything, but I check just to
make sure that I don't use the last
versions. And because a lot of um
>> [clears throat]
>> the projects have many people working on
it, I don't just update and hope that
everything keeps working. So I need to
test it anyway.
Yeah. Yeah, oh yeah, yeah, because
you're working with like people and
other devs, then you don't need to
upgrade it yourself. You don't take this
responsibility anyway. No, but also I
can just update and deploy because if it
gives an issue or it has an update that
that deletes functions or has deep the
duplicated issues,
then the entire system stops on certain
points and I can't have that. So
every update we need to test.
Yeah, makes sense. And AI can do that
probably.
No, no, no, yeah, it's going to Oh yeah,
I'm done. Yeah, but you missed half of
the code base. No, no, but I'm done. No,
no,
you missed You missed half the code
base. Oh yeah, you're right. Yeah,
you're right. Let me retry it. Uh
let me try again.
Uh okay. So
Okay.
So should we plan some stuff with HTML
now? Yes, let's see what you can do.
Okay. So
uh puff puff.
Back. I'm going to close that. I'm going
to close that. Puff puff puff. Okay. Oh.
Uh okay.
Uh we're going to do the introduction at
marker 26. Yes.
Okay. So
uh
Here are the
It's correct. It's It's guarded.
Um okay.
Are you still planning with MD files?
Maybe that's not the better output
that you can have.
And what about HTML files? That's what
Tarik from Entropic
wrote about last week.
Uh is planning everything with HTMLs
because it's prettier than MD the files.
You can actually like draw some charts
and stuff to have better plans.
And we are going to
um
build a demo. Yeah, do demo, right?
Yeah. We are going to uh demo that
workflow uh for you. So, uh if you are
intrigued, watch the video.
Woo!
>> Yes.
We are going to make the the files shiny
and fancy. Yeah.
That's for sure. Okay. So, yeah. Yeah,
did you ever try it before the live
stream or like this week or I wanted to
try it, but you know, I said create a
documentation and just did MD by
default.
Okay. And then I asked for HTML and HTML
was just like still the MD,
but only uh like H1 tag in front of it
instead of one hashtag. Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, because yeah, Markdown can also
read the MD file uh HTML file. So, yeah.
Yeah. So, it didn't do what I wanted to
do.
Uh but let's try again again together
then.
Yes. Uh so, uh HTML is the new Markdown.
I've stopped writing Markdown file for
almost everything and switched to using
Cloud Code to generate HTML for me. This
is why.
4 million tweet on an article like yeah,
it's it's not.
Uh the article is like 11 million
impression and then like the retweet of
the article is like 4 million.
Not.
Uh
Markdown has become the dominant file
format used by agent to communicate with
us. It's simple, portable, and has some
rich text capability, and it's easy for
you to edit that.
Claude has even gotten surprisingly good
at using ASCII to make diagram inside
markdown files.
But, as agents have become more and more
powerful, I have felt that markdown has
become a restricted format. I find it
difficult to read a markdown file of
more than 100 of lines.
Um
Uh I want richer visualization, color,
and diagram, and I want to be able to
share them easily. So, basically, you
get your you get your plan, you get the
output of the plan, it's a HTML file. We
can you I guess you can compare You can
even like have different uh output of
the plan or
exactly what you are doing, right? Like
when you have three version of the
output, you can visualize uh
whatever you are doing directly into the
plan. That I can see that powerful. For
example, if you want to redesign a
component,
you can have three different version in
a preview HTML, right? Yes.
That would
That would be cool.
Um
I'm also increasingly not editing this
file myself. I Bro, I never edited a
markdown file Yeah. He has to write a
blog, right?
>> [snorts]
>> Uh when I do make edits, I usually
prompt in Claude to edit them. Yes,
okay. Which remove one of the markdown
largest benefits. Uh Okay.
Uh I started prefer HTML as a output
format instead of markdown and
increasingly see the uh being used by
other other Claude code teams, which is
why
uh stuff from example and here. Boom.
So,
here
the unreasonable effectiveness of
effectiveness of HTML.
Uh 20 self-contained HTML files an agent
produced instead of a wall of markdown.
Okay.
So, three code approach Yeah, exactly.
So, that's
I can see why it's powerful.
Yeah, you have more more options, more
possibilities.
Like that that makes sense. Like yeah, I
have some
I have some different different way of
coding it and then I can read it more
easily. That that's cool. Visual
direction, yeah, no task.
Yeah, that's cool. Illustration
illustration all. Okay, so you have
empty state of
uh
of the plan, timeline. Yeah, that's
cool.
Okay, so yeah, that's not that's lit.
Open question, do we allow editing or
delete and repost? Okay.
Code review.
Annotate pull request.
Uh
PR write-up. Yeah, okay, that's cool.
Okay, okay, okay. That's that's pretty
cool.
Uh module map, design.
Yeah, that's lit. Like for design front
end and stuff, that's that's
interesting. And that's the plan, right?
This file is supposed to be the plan at
the output plan that we we will have,
right? Yeah, but this is more like a
brand book.
Yeah, but that's also a plan. You can
choose and change like the colors and
stuff like that. And
later in the article, you can even like
have Google to change the plan directly.
Like interactively. But that's almost
like a front end
uh
app. Like Cloud Pods
UI could actually do that inside the
chat conversation.
Yeah.
Like they they could use markdown to
generate a good UI for it. But this is a
good example, but just for planning and
communication inside with your agent,
I don't see any benefits. Like it's
agent to human, not agent to agent,
right? Yeah, or human to agent. Yeah.
Uh
I mean, you meant to agent? No, you you
still like
prompting.
Yeah, you're still prompting, but
if you set up the entire document, you
just throw it into another agent and say
build this.
Mhm. Uh
And I prefer MD files.
But maybe HTML gives better results. I
don't know. Oh, yeah, because okay, so
yeah, I I I don't know if you explain
that in the article, but yeah, like
because there is more text to it, right?
So, is it scrapping all of the tags
to send it as a context?
Exactly. I like how clean the MD files
are. Yeah.
Uh, animated illustration. Okay, so
that's basically okay, you plan
something and then you have an
illustration of what it can be uh
after. So, fair enough.
Uh, touch but while HTML information
density, okay, okay. Popular data. Okay,
so it's visually yeah, okay.
That's
uh yeah.
That's is Wait. Bam. That's
No. That
That is better than that. Yes. Thank
you.
>> Yes. Yes.
Uh, visual clarity and ease of reading,
okay, blah blah blah. Ease of sharing.
Uh
are fairly hard to share since most
browser do not render the natively, you
often add them as attachment to email or
messages. Yeah, well, why are you
sending MD files to people who don't
know how to code? That's stupid. Yeah, I
haven't but yeah, maybe they work with
with a team and they share plans.
Yeah.
Well, I have a shared folder, right? You
don't attach it to an email, but
Yeah. You just convert it to a PDF.
The MD file and share that PDF to your
customers. You can add default styling
and you have the same setup as the HTML.
Uh yeah, with HTML it's like a job load.
For example, in A3 you can share the
link easily. Yeah, okay.
>> [snorts]
>> Uh yeah, okay. So, to share that to
share the plan, he send he upload it to
A3, share the link. Yeah, okay. The
chance of someone actually reading your
spec report or PR write-up is much
much higher if it's actually I mean, on
GitHub, if you could have like a HTML
preview,
uh that would be lit.
And that's perfect. Because GitHub can
only read MD files right now.
>> Yeah. Yeah, it seems you're right now
and maybe that's not going to be the
highest priority for this week. Well, I
think it's also security issues, right?
Uh HTML it's like an email.
If you don't authorize JavaScript, then
it's fine. Yeah, yeah, then it's fine.
But if you do, then that's not good.
>> Yeah, it's just a presentation
presentation layer, right?
Uh two-way interaction, yes, okay.
Uh
apply Yeah, so yeah, you can have those
interaction toggle and then it will
update your plan. That's kind of cool.
Like it's an interactive plan.
Uh pass the result back to the agent. Uh
HTML can allow you to interact with the
document, for example, blah blah blah.
Okay.
Data ingestion, why use CloudCode to
make HTML5 instead of CloudAI or Cloud
design, for example.
One of the biggest reasons is
all the context CloudCode can ingest.
Oh, so you increase the size of the
context because you want to send HTML,
really?
Really? They earn more money if they do.
Yeah.
Oh, isn't it a
Because you're spending more tokens.
Yeah.
And
I'm really curious if we can test for an
um
asking the AI agent to do it in the in a
MD file and a HTML file, make it as
optimized as possible, and then give him
both files and ask him which one he
prefers, which one is most optimized and
what what is the most cheapest to
process.
We're going to try that right after.
Yes.
Um be file beside the file system cloud
code
additional context um
Okay. It's joyful. Okay. Yes. Okay.
Yeah. Woo.
Yeah, you're just going to pay like 250
instead of 200 a month. He should have
started with this one. Yeah.
But to get started, I'm a little bit
afraid that people will read the article
and turn it into HTML skills or
something.
What there might be some value in that.
I want to emphasize I don't need to do
much to get close to do this. You can
just ask make an HTML file make the HTML
artifact. Okay. So, that's it. Yes.
>> Uh the trick is knowing that you want
the artifact to do and how you might use
it. Okay.
To make this more concrete, I've made
many different HTML files. So, yeah,
that's the effective method. That's the
document we just read.
>> Yeah. Specs planning exploration HTML is
a rich canvas for Claude to dive into a
problem.
Yeah, okay. Yeah, and you can select the
the option and that's it. Uh prompt, I'm
sure what direction to take on
onboarding screen. Generate six dis-
distinctly different approaches, vary
layout tone and density, and lay down
into a single HTML file. Okay, so you
you ask for the output to be HTML.
Uh exploring other way to implement
something in code code review
What?
Markdown file
But with HTML we can render diff
annotation.
That feels complicated. Yeah, it just
makes a makes a
a better overview of what code is used
and how much tokens is used and
everything.
Help me review this PR by creating a
HTML artifact that described it. Okay.
Yeah, you just get a dashboard. Yeah.
>> [snorts]
>> Uh blah block
uh create PR with your PR understand
topic in code design and prototype.
Okay, design I understand design that
makes sense.
Uh report research learning. Okay, your
rate limit works.
Uh product for school that's lit. Yes.
Like yeah.
That that that will kill teachers.
Uh
example prompt I don't understand how
rate limit actually works with the
relevant code and produce a single HTML
explainer page blah blah blah. Okay,
cool.
Custom editing interface. Yeah, so I I
did that once. Um
I wanted to explore like some design for
component and I asked [clears throat] it
like five different version of it and I
had a preview and then implement like a
version three and that's cool. Like
that's actually cool.
Uh
I need to re-prioritize like selling in
a ticket whatever blah blah blah.
Frequently asked question everything.
Okay, is it less token efficient? While
Markdown often use fewer token I found
that the added expressiveness of HTML
and the much
higher likelihood of me reading it means
I get overall better output. Okay. With
the 1 million context window in Opus 4.7
the increased token usage is not really
noticeable. Yeah, because the rest of
the
the of the model is too expensive that
if it's
you don't see it.
>> but still this is a stupid answer. Yeah.
Isn't it less token efficient? Yes or
no? And then you get a full [__]
answer, but he doesn't answer it. Yeah,
he says it doesn't matter. That's that's
the answer. He answered to say yeah,
it's more expensive. Yeah.
>> [clears throat]
>> Uh when do you do this when do you use
markdown file now? I've honestly stopped
using markdown. Okay.
Uh, who have you the
HTML files I tend to just open it in a
browser locally upload it to S3 if you
want to share a link. Yeah, because
that's the issue, eh? If you send it to
a customer who is not an IT guy, he
doesn't know how to open HTML. Yeah, but
is your customer is going to
check all of your plan? No, but he is
making reports and everything in HTML.
I prefer sending them a PDF.
Yeah.
Maybe I don't know how good Claude is.
If you say convert this to an PDF.
Mhm.
Wait, how do you generate your PDF then?
Yeah, first you make your HTML.
And then you just optimize it and then
I've written a script that just converts
it to PDF, but you can also ask Claude
to convert it to PDF. Mhm.
Yeah, like you have a little Yeah, HTML
to PDF libraries things. Yeah, I do. And
I prefer the the MD to PDF because you
can add every styling that you want.
Mhm.
Okay.
Uh, but
markdown is basically a simplified
version of HTML anyway. Yeah. So, there
is that. Uh, what about version control?
One of the biggest downside of HTML is
noisy and hard to review compared to
markdown. Okay.
How do I get a Claude to match my test
not making it ugly from 10 designs code?
Okay.
You can then use that design file as a
reference for the staying loop blah blah
blah.
Uh, cool. Okay, so we have that.
Uh, thanks. That's fine.
That's all stuff. Okay, so Kapathy
replied to it. Uh, this works really
well by the way. At the end of your
query ask your LLM to structure your
response
response as HTML. Then use the generated
file in your browser. Uh-huh.
Uh
in my opinion, audio is the human
preferred input to AI.
Whisper flow is
lit. Lit. Uh but vision, image,
animation, video is the preferred output
for them. Around a third of our brain
are massively parallel processors
dedicated to vision, okay?
Uh I think we'll see a progression that
takes advantage of raw text, markdown,
HTML, interactive neural video
simulation. Lol.
Uh the extrapolation though the
technology doesn't exist just yet and in
some kind of interactive video generated
directly. Yeah, okay.
Uh telling you that the input output
mind meld between human and AI is going
is ongoing and there is a lot of work to
do and significant progress to be made.
Maybe for all of the way to learning
SQL. Okay, whatever.
For what is worth exploring at the
current stage, hot tip, try ask for
HTML. Okay, we're going to try that now.
Uh move from markdown and give it AI
which I can
and uh Matt Pocock like a big guy like
sharing a [__] ton of AI content.
Try that too. So, yeah, should we Yeah,
let's try it.
Cuz all the big IT guys who are really
smart are now getting so many views and
impressions with just the notification
of ask for HTML. Yeah. So, uh let's do
exactly the same [__] Yes. [laughter]
Uh so, you want to do it?
What? Do you have it open?
Uh I have a new project with nothing and
T3 code ready, but uh that's it. You can
>> Yeah, let's do it. I have nothing open.
I closed everything when you said I have
it ready. Oh.
Okay.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh so, I'm going to do that to that T3
cards. T3 cards. Um
So, this is T3 cards. T3 card we have to
just record.
Theo
Shout out.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you, Theo.
Okay, so bam, bam,
oh [__]
Like
Can I
resize correctly? Okay, so
uh above chat, I'm already in it.
Uh okay, so
Uh is that going to work?
>> going to type? Are you Do you have
Whisper also active? I have Whisper on
this computer. Cool.
Um
So
What we are going to
do an app
to check if the
the repository is using the TanStack
that has been compromised. Yes.
>> [laughter]
>> And hope it says no.
Yeah.
Uh I want to build a micro app um to
check the vulnerability of open source
project.
Nice. Micro app to check the
vulnerabilities.
Back. I'm going to do plan. Okay. Open
source project uh that have been
impacted by the latest attack.
I'm going to give you some
back.
Uh okay, I'm going to get the tweet.
Uh what was that?
I forgot.
Um
Okay. So still have it open.
Bam.
Uh where is the postmortem so I can
share it to code right away?
Uh update blah blah blah.
Look at it.
Update.
Where's the postmortem?
Okay, yes.
Cool.
TanStack NPM package, okay. So,
uh
path
the latest attic
of the TanStack
uh
packages.
Nice. See, the accent and stuff, it's
perfect. It understands you perfectly.
>> Yeah.
Uh all of the
uh
impacted package are listed in that
article.
path
Uh
plan the app and I want the output of
the plan in HTML file. So, create a HTML
artifact for the plan.
Also add it in MD, so we have both, so
we can compare.
And also add the MD file, so we can
compare uh the outputs.
And I want you to tell me how many how
many token you use to generate the plan
in MD file and HTML.
And the app uh will also generate HTML
report.
That's clear? We're good?
>> Yes.
Uh so oh, I'm a uh yeah, so I'm using
4.6 and I'm on high effort reasoning.
Yes.
I start by exploring the current code
base and fetching the article about
TanStack and understand the scope. And
the repository is empty. So, let's go.
Okay. So, that's it. That's planning.
Let's [clears throat] see how good it
is. Yeah.
Project directory is empty and I have a
web fetch tool already. Okay, cool.
Uh yeah, okay. So, how's your life, bro?
Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> It's like this, always waiting on the
AI. I argue No, you just like spawn like
five of the prompts and then you you can
put you you can you create like five
side projects Yeah. and then you wait
for the main one. And then you type a
prompt from project one in project three
and you get the the answer. I cannot
find this.
And you say, "How stupid are you?" And
then you notice that you're in the wrong
project. Yeah, exactly.
Uh, do you tell him intelligence on the
attack? No, let me design the
implementation plan. Let's go.
The project directory is empty. Okay,
cool.
Nice. Initialize guide. Get. Uh, do you
use T3 cuts?
Nope. Oh.
I I I'm still working as CLI.
Yeah, okay. Uh, it's honestly, I think
T3 cut is better than the CLI.
Yeah. It's It's It is the issue. I
We keep switching so many times. I don't
have the time to keep switching. I
Okay, don't switch to T3 cuts because
soon you will you will switch to ship
cut. Yes. That's the That's the better
one. Yeah, exactly.
But like for example like in
T3 cut when I like Okay, so
Why I want to that? Yes. Okay, so you
can load the whatever like local folder,
whatever, whatever. Path.
Ship ship show. And I'm going to do open
Sora. Yeah.
Uh, but Okay, so in the prompt um
in the prompt app, you can switch the
agents.
Yeah. So, you have access to all of the
providers. Mhm. [clears throat] And you
can switch the contact and you can even
switch Uh, it's not a feature yet. It's
not implemented, but it will. You can
start with um
Opus and then you can switch to Codex in
the same context window. Yeah, that's
cool. You can easily check it. Exactly.
And uh, yeah, so you can use Cursor,
open code, Gemini, and GitHub Copilot.
Uh
Okay,
you can use GitHub Copilot. Let's go.
Yeah.
Isn't GitHub using GitHub Copilot? I
don't think so.
I hope not.
Uh excellent have detail. Okay, uh let's
think faster.
Hey, you put it on high. Yeah.
I only want smart stuff. Yeah, yeah. So,
you're saying burn more tokens. Yeah,
exactly.
>> Ask me more money, think longer.
And and if it is a better result, I
don't know. Yeah. I mean, yeah, like
there is some like a Tarik uh
Tarik or Tarik?
Okay, the guy from Anthropic uh told us
that yeah, it's going to burn more
token, but uh it's better. Yeah, yeah.
Trust me. Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> Is that Tarik or Tarik? It I don't know.
What sounds best? I think.
Anthropic
ic ic
Ah.
Yeah, Tarik. Okay. My bad.
Uh oh, I was not sharing the screen.
Okay, cool.
Uh let's go, let's go. Like sibling's
project structure for style reference.
What?
Okay.
Just
Just do it. Uh there is no sibling's
structure or project to follow. Just
Just show us the Just do a setup. Yeah.
Uh tak tak. Okay. Last time I told that
the first thing I said is I need to show
customer a proof of concept or an MVP,
and I need it done in 5 minutes.
Please create a working setup. And it
was so fast. Really? Yeah.
But you were in the medium?
No, no, yeah, I'm in a in the project
itself. Yeah, but you were in medium or
is it not?
>> Oh, no, no, I was on Codex X High. Okay.
And I just explained like I'm already
running late.
>> [laughter]
>> I need to set up right now.
And it it it said, "Okay, I will be fast
and I will give you a minimum needed
code base just to get it working." And
it it it it worked. Bam.
Uh I have all of the intelligence and a
detailed design. Let me read the
existing memory index and then write a
comprehensive plan file. Cool. I can
write the files. Okay, it's coming. It's
coming. I can't feel it. It's coming.
Uh maybe we should have started the that
and then talk about the security. Yeah.
Let's go. Uh
tag
and path.
Yeah, what is it talking about?
Uh
tag.
Yeah.
Finish uh something else.
Oh.
Oops.
Base.
Yeah.
Is it is it still talking about the
Cuz it wants to go well on the system.
Okay.
I hope you guys understand this is going
to keep gaining loss. Yeah. Yes. It is
just the beginning. Mhm.
The reason behind this is developer
pushing code.
Oh, someone who is new using NPM. Is
there a centralized agent consumer list
for these notices? What's the best
protection mechanism?
Uh
generate new version, disable auto
update or home brew if using.
Don't use random skill from anybody.
Highly recommend a second box for any
dev work for only dev work. Yeah, yeah,
staging server.
Yeah.
Oh.
Yeah, but if you are on a bigger project
that people rely on, then you you
already have it. You don't auto update
and push. You you check what you update,
you push it to staging, [clears throat]
test it, and then push it to live.
Uh should I create them in the project?
Yes.
Project root.
Auto can tracking. I can estimate token
based on puts.
Auto can be English word. Okay.
Include this in a footer? Yes.
Uh both file? Yes.
The app name is shield check. That's
[snorts] perfect. [laughter]
That's perfect.
So then we can check like T3 codes and
then if uh the T3 code has been
impacted, uh then I'm using the app. So
I guess I'm safe or not.
>> [laughter]
>> Just pull out your internet connection
out of your laptop.
>> [clears throat]
>> Oh, wait. Maybe.
Uh
because
I'm going to
That's the plan.
But I'm using T3 codes to plan.
So I have the
because I'm going to validate the plan,
right?
>> Mhm.
So if I validate the plan, then I will
have Yeah, it's it's already
it's already planning the whole app.
Yeah. Yeah, but that's not a problem. We
want to see it in an empty and an HTML.
Yeah, but that is where we are planning
on the file create first in the project
root.
Okay, so I'm going to tell him to just
give me the
plan. Okay.
All scanners module. Okay.
I want to review the plan first.
So you are going to just create those
two plans in the repository, and then
we're going to approve the rest of all
of the steps.
I want to review the plans.
Okay.
Wait for me to confirm
uh the plan before implementing the
rest.
Ah.
Documentary verification. Let me know if
there I should start building. Okay,
I will create just plan MD. Let's go.
Walking. Walking.
I love AI. It's so smart.
Okay, cool. Uh path replace replace.
Um
uh pinning lock way
lock lock your tree. Yeah.
Let's go on this.
NPM compromise in ongoing many show
related attack.
Is that still going?
Yeah, well, everybody is writing about
it just to get the views, right? Yeah.
Recommend action immediate triage run
on all rooter in it files in your
dependency tree match against
Really?
Rotate all secrets immediately on any
system. Revoke GitHub action or this is
a mission critical. Yeah, that's not
That's crazy. Audit cloud and VS cards.
Open search mistrial blah blah blah.
Yeah.
We have been online over two hours no
stealing creds. Regardless, I just came
to say hello.
Oh my god.
Domain also display a sign or
Uh they they took it down. Like the kids
10 stack is down.
Yeah, they don't have much choice. They
need to make sure that people don't get
infected.
I see Mistral AI Mistral open search
quad rail
It's nuts.
Uh file change okay.
I mean
yeah it's
mental.
mental
And socket.dev looks legit.
jQuery find a companion of open source
package
maintenance
whatever whatever will protect you from
vulnerable and malicious packages.
Oh, can you install that?
free for individual developer and small
team looking to stay secure
unlimited developer and repo 1,000 Oh,
interesting.
developer security for team of all size
Okay. My question is what does it check?
Because if it checks the signature that
was legit.
Yeah, but I'm pretty sure they would
send you an email if so you can monitor
all of the package.
I'm going to I'm going to
I I will check that later.
Tag path replace uh window T3 no
T3 yes cool
path
tag Can I zoom?
Uh can I
uh I can't toggle. There's no toggle.
No.
Cool.
Uh tag tag tag Okay, both plan and
artifact are created. Uh
3,000 4,000 for the
uh the plan.dmg and 6,000
So, yeah, almost double. Yeah, 50% more
expensive.
Estimate output, markdown, estimate
input token. Okay, 1,000. Yeah, so
estimated
Wait, what?
Okay.
Oh, yeah, on the output token. Yes,
okay.
Uh HTML version used 63% more output
token due to the marker best care
signing. Yeah, whatever. Open plan.
Okay, cool. Cool.
Open it. Yeah.
Q so
five five
Yeah. So, if I open
Q so
base window
Wow.
So, that's the MD file.
Uh that's quite long.
But, that's that's readable. I mean
Yeah, but
I don't know the the code editors I use,
they always have a second screen beside
it when I open an MD file. So, I can see
code and preview.
Uh I Okay, so on Q so it's an extension
where you can uh preview the markdown.
Uh oh, preview. Right, look. Yeah,
and then it's readable. Yeah.
Yeah, like uh Yeah, there is nothing
crazy here, right? Uh to uh
uh to to review anyway. So, okay, and
now I'm going to open
the MD uh
HTML file.
five
five five open in
browser
five
Oh, okay.
Yeah, I can I can open in QSO. They have
a brother.
Wow, it's the same [__] but purple.
Yeah, different colors. Okay, that's
cool. Compare It's like bootstrap
styling over it in dark mode.
Yeah.
Uh okay, so later bam uh generated by
Opus 4.6. Chill chick chill chick
implemented plan ba ba bam. Uh
generation matrix HTML ba ba bam. Okay,
self-contained yes inline CSS no
external resources.
Uh yeah, that's more yeah, it's more
readable. It's not that crazy, right?
Um okay, so I'm curious now in the in
the AI if you now just clear the entire
history
drop in both files the MD and the HTML
and ask it which file is best optimized
for him to start coding the project. Uh
Okay, so I clear the context? Yes.
Uh
Can I clear it?
I don't know if slash clear works.
Okay. And just drag in both files.
It's so smart. It's so smart.
Okay. Uh
What the [__]
Oh, it is coming in preview.
Files.
Or you can even say uh because it's in
the in the folder already. Yeah. Yeah.
Bring the folder like back back.
History uh I think uh history yeah
history will not
work.
Uh okay, so
I'm going to save some token. Okay,
medium.
Uh Read both plan uh files and tell me
which one will is more consistent for
you and more useful.
And cheaper to implement.
Back back. Good? Mhm. Let's see what it
answers.
Back. Okay. Okay. I have but I mean for
example for components I could
I like that. I like the output. Again
like I want to redesign whatever
something and then I
I ask Claude to give me three version of
that React component redesign and
then we can even integrate with that
preview. I did that for example for the
splash screen of the
of the ship code because it was only on
the splash screen of the app and I said
give me a preview of the splash screen
and we're going to we work with that and
it was interesting for sure. Yeah. I
would also say for your own customers is
better. You can just create a HTML,
print it to PDF and give it to them and
say hey, here it is shiny and new and
tell me what you like.
I read both file they contain identical
content the same sheet check plan in two
format. Mhm. Lines 200 for the MD file
and almost 600 570 for the plain HTML.
Estimate tokens three
3.8
6.2 so
final to knows high pure content low 200
line of CSS HTML boilerplate. Yeah.
Consistency
table header code block and unambiguous.
That's interesting.
Plain.md is a clear winner for on all
three criteria.
Huh.
Recommendation use plain.md lol.
Yeah.
It works both but HTML is just more nice
to look at and and more expensive to
use.
I mean, that's the all experimentation.
Yeah. [laughter]
I mean, we just wanted the plan, right?
It's just for as output plan. So, yeah,
for the general evaluation, yeah, like
Okay, okay, so If you use it for
internal planning, then use the MD
files. If you want to do reporting and
and use it for sharing with people, you
can do the HTML. That's what I think.
Yeah, that makes sense. Yeah, okay. So,
like, yeah, it's it's like almost
don't use ever like just one, use both,
basically.
Yeah.
I think that's it.
Yeah. So, yeah, okay, that's it. That
was nice demo. Good job, Tim.
Uh
What? Extra camera? No, I don't want the
extra camera. I want to do the
conclusion.
Uh tak. I'm going to kill that later. Uh
okay, cool. So, Mitchell, are you going
to use HTML for now? [laughter]
If I want to share something nice for
you, I'm going to use HTML, but as soon
as I want it to be optimized and use it
for planning internally, all all MD
files.
How about you?
I mean, again, I I can see your use case
for components, for sure. If I want to
redesign a component, I will ask for a
preview in HTML, cuz that doesn't like
for a couple of percent of token more,
like, I would rather iterate on content.
Uh
on on the HTML with the HTML files to
redesign something. And I'm using Claude
for design and more like
all of the rest of the execution, I use
Codex anyway. I don't I still don't use
chat GPT 5.5 for design because it's the
taste of the model is [__] So, I will
definitely use Cloud and the front-end
skill to do front-end stuff
and delegate all of the implementation,
the rest of the implementation to
Codex.
Perfect. Yeah.
Nice. Okay, awesome. We will not be
That was it. Yeah. We have a good demo
if we have did like a 26-minute
introduction.
>> [laughter]
>> But that that's that's talent, man.
That's talent. Yes.
So, Mitchell, thank you so much for your
time and everyone in the chat and in the
if you are watching the video until the
end, uh
please subscribe, like, share it with
your friends because we need it. Uh we
are still
We miss some subscribers to 1 million
subscribers. So, it's time to time to
subscribe. Yeah, let them come in. Yeah.
Uh
and that's it. Bye.
See you next week. See you next week.